<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ePortflio on Michael Healy</title>
    <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ePortflio on Michael Healy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Your Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/academic/project/eportfolios/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Preperation, Curriculum Design, and TA&#39;s</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/wpa-dis/wpa-dis-ab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 16:26:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/wpa-dis/wpa-dis-ab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coxwell-Teague, Deborah, and Ronald F. Lunsford eds. &lt;em&gt;First-Year Composition: From Theory to Practice&lt;/em&gt;. Parlor Press, Anderson, SC, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This edited collection provides theoretical background for a hypothetical first-year composition class. Coxwell-Teague and Lunsford ask the contributers&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &amp;ldquo;what they would do if they taigh semester-long first-year composition course at their schools and if they knew such courses were to be the only colelge-level compositiong course the students would take&amp;rdquo; (preface viii)? Each chapter is seperated into two halves: theoretical frame and a syllabus. In the first section of each chapter, the contributors offer the rationales for their design of the course, each highly representative of their own interests and their contexts. The second half of the chapter are supplementary materials, each with a syllabus, and many with assignmen sheets. Overall, the collection offers a snapshot of what many scholars in Rhetoric and Composition see as the important features of this class. There are many commonalities among them, where FYC does not focus on grammar, persuasion, or on the &amp;ldquo;improvement of writing&amp;rdquo;. Overall, the colelction offers an interesting look at what the core teaching practices and focuses of the discipline are, and where they fit within First-Year composition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pytlik, Betty P, and Sarah Liggett. &lt;em&gt;Preparing College Teachers of Writing: Histories, Theories, Programs, Practices&lt;/em&gt;. Oxford UP, Oxford, 2002.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This edited collection examines issues of curriculum design, teacher preperation, graduate teaching assistants, labor, pedagogy, and practice. It has an extensive list of contributors &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and the chapters were organized aroudn the themes histories, theories, programs, and practices. The provided chapters offer a snapshot into program design, preperation, curriculum, education, support, and local contexts for a variety of teaching assistants, adjuncts, faculty, and professors teaching college writing. The chapters tended to reflect the local nature of the program, outside of some that took a winder stance such as Yancey&amp;rsquo;s heurstic for curriculum design. Overall, the chapters tended to get repetitive, with many offering similar types of programs with various levels teacher preperation and support. There were things to be learned in terms of the framing, content, and ongoing programs that teachers of composition need, and how to structure programs and curriculums. This volume, as compared to the others, was light on theory but had lots of on-the-ground types of insights and explorations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Petraglia, Joseph. &lt;em&gt;Reconceiving Writing: Rethinking Writing Instruction&lt;/em&gt;. Mahwah, NJ, 1995.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This edited collection rethinks and theorizes what writing is. With this theoretical exploration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Chris Anson, Suresh Canagarajah, Douglas Hesse, Asao Inoue, Paula Mathieu, Teresa Redd, Alexander Reid, Jody Shipka, Howard Tinberg, Victor Villanueva, Elizabeth Wardle, Doug Downs, and Kathleen Blake Yancey.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;Betty P. Pytlik; Stephen Wilhoit; Krsti A. Sandy; Irwin Weiser; Darin Payne and Theresa Enos; Kathleen Blake Yancey; Shirley K Rose and Margaret J. Finders; Judith Goleman; Christine Farris; Rebecca J. Rickly and Susanmarie Harrington; Katrina M. Powell, Peggy O&amp;rsquo;Neill, Casandra Mach Phillips, and Brian Huot; Katherine K. Gottschalk; Betty Bamberg; Chris Burnam and Rebecca Jackson; Paul Anderson, Todd DeLuca, and Lisa Rosenberger; Christine Hult and Lynn Meeks; Muriel Harris; Sally Barr Ebest; Wanda Martin and Charles Paine; Gita Das Bender; Michael C. Flanigan; Thomas E. Recchio; Barry Thatcher; Donna Qualley; Margaret Lindgren; Sarah Liggett
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theories of Composition ePortfolio</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my Spring 2017 Composition Theory ePortfolio. The links go to the individual components that have been selected for inclusion. The selections here represent some of the work of this semester though is not inclusive. I also intend for these selections and reflections to look back to what I brought into the class, what I learned here, and forward to new contexts. At the bottom of this page are links to and brief descriptions of each artifact collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall reflection for the ePortfolio will guide you through the reading and connections. As you read through the reflection, the artifacts that I mention will be linked and open in new tabs, so that specifics of what I mention will be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-reflection-reflection&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reflection&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Final Reflection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This serves as a synthesis of the artifacts collected within this ePortfolio. This reflection works with the themes and readings of the class to illustrate the selections, while also looking beyond the classroom context to how the learning and artifacts function more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;triptych-plus-project-triptych&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;triptych&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Triptych Plus Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project examines three different perspectives on composition: Homebrewing Community, a SpaceX hosted webcast for a rocket launch, and Malea Powell&amp;rsquo;s 2012 CCCCs chairs address. The above link will take you directly to the reflective overlay, which then links to the individual panels of the triptych. This organization mirrors the theological art use of a triptych, with the overall theme opening up to reveal the interior workings, which is present in the &lt;a href=&#34;triptychreflection&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Triptych Plus Reflective Overlay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;perspective-project-perspectives&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;perspectives&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Perspective Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This link connects to my video interview with Ned Stuckey-French on composition and his composition process. The video essay, based around the recorded interview is featured, along with an additional reflection and provided links on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;below-are-three-selections-with-reflections-from-the-class-this-semester&#34;&gt;Below are three selections, with reflections, from the class this semester.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-one-and-reflection-situating-composition-studies-selection1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection One and Reflection: Situating Composition Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This selection is an SRR that examines the history and evolution of composition in universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-two-and-reflection-processing-assumptions-selection2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection Two and Reflection: Processing Assumptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post that takes a different perspective on the development of composition as a discipline based on the research being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-three-and-reflection-writing-program-acronyms-considering-contexts-systems-and-locales-selection3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection Three and Reflection: Writing Program Acronyms: Considering Contexts, Systems, and Locales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SRR examines the history and taxonomies of different WAC/WID programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-outside-artifact-selections&#34;&gt;Two Outside Artifact Selections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry-https-atplaywithcomposition-wordpress-com-exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://atplaywithcomposition.wordpress.com/exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exploratory 2: Interest and Inquiry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an assignment prompt from my 2135 class that I&amp;rsquo;m teaching this semester. I chose this because of the pedagogical connections between composition theory and what I am teaching. I also chose it because the prompt and activity was influenced by work in collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities-https-digitalscholars-wordpress-com-2017-02-12-look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalscholars.wordpress.com/2017/02/12/look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Look at all this Stuff! On Playing, Printing, and Virtual Reality in the Digital Humanities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post that I composed as an introduction to a digital scholars meeting. This was a synthesis of the readings and materials for the week, and was situated within a very specific rhetorical ecology and responded to a set of exigencies. I also chose it due to the content of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-abstract-abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Final Project Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connects to my final project abstract, which involves a short study from my teaching this semester that looks at play, voice, and pedagogy, and seeks to study the efficacy of play in students use of voice in 2135. I am targeting SAMLA for the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icons made by Freepik from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flaticon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.flaticon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Abstract</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 22:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/abstract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my final project I am proposing a conference concurrent-session presentation that uses research from my classroom this semester. I am studying the efficacy of play as an organizational and pedagogical theory in ENC 2135. I am interested in students; perceptions on play within the composition classroom, especially in the development of voice and agency in their writing. I have anecdotally seen it as a positive influence through my teaching, but I want something more empirical that I can build from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do the study I have prepared a materials release form and a short survey to distribute to students. I have arranged for the distribution and collection of these materials. I will use these responses, student reflections, and student evaluations to read and code for play, voice, and agency. I will be focusing on a peer review exercise that has students speed date a draft, a collaborative activity that asks students to inhabit inquiry, and the semester reflection letter for their ePortfolios. I will develop a coding scheme (at this point I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if it will be deductive or inductive) to examine the written materials. I will use the coding, surveys, and my own observations to help triangulate the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to see first, what students think about a play infused classroom through these activities, and second, to see if there is evidence of efficacy within their reflective writings, evaluations, and surveys. I am developing a conference proposal based on this study for SAMLA, with two potential panels of interest: &lt;em&gt;Voices From The Twenty-First-Century College Composition Classroom&lt;/em&gt; Or &lt;em&gt;Critical Thinking In The Rhet-Comp Classroom&lt;/em&gt; I see this resonating with either of these panels, but I am also willing to submit through the general call for papers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectual Whack-a-Mole</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/triptychreflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 17:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/triptychreflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In looking back through my exploration of &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/triptych#hombrewing&#34;&gt;homebrewing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory//triptych#spacex&#34;&gt;a SpaceX webcast&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/triptych#powell&#34;&gt;Malea Powell’s CCCCs address&lt;/a&gt;, I see trends coalesce around the social nature of composing and composition. The different composing practices and compositions of these three artifacts are all situated in-between multiple voices, knowledges, places, spaces, and practices. Composition, from looking at these three pieces of the triptych, assembles into a communal inscription by a person or persons onto the world, with some specific and rhetorical aim to the process. All three illustrate the aspects of ecologies in which compositions, writers, audiences, process, and literacies circulate within and between each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I noticed was how highly contextual composition is. Examining the homebrewing community provided a range of different and situated composing practices as potential examples—troubleshooting a brew, sharing knowledge, sharing brewing stories, developing a recipe, or brewing itself—that are all related to the same basic activity and have a similar knowledge foundation, but require potentially different responses. The SpaceX hosted webcast was also highly contextual, with the focus on the composition being the events of the launch, the customer, an experimental rocket landing, and the return to flight after an accident investigation. Malea Powell’s address was situated within the context of CCCCs, but also with an audience of educators and composition professionals. The talk was also situated within the context of St. Louis and the stories related to place, people, and erasure that were assembled in the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, composition is used to express and share the knowledge and expertise of a community of practice. In the homebrew beer community, composition practices are used to disseminate and share best practices, scientific insights, personal experiences, and in the assemblage of ingredients for recipes. Composition in used to communicate between members and initiates of the community on how to brew beer and the effects of different approaches, where the assemblage of ingredients, methods, time, people, and temperature, all have effects on the end-product. The SpaceX hosted webcast had as a purpose the sharing of knowledge and expertise through a variety of professionals, data, and images to share what was events during the launch coverage, and was presented in a way to be interesting to experts and to novices. And lastly, Malea Powell’s address was an assemblage of voices and important issues that she felt needed to be presented and addressed. She drew on a plurality of voices to showcase a depth of knowledge in an issue for a knowledgeable community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, composition and composing can be used to learn, explore, and express interest or membership within different communities. It can also be used to exclude others from that community. I found this aspect most apparent in Malea Powell’s talk where compositions can be a means through which hegemonic power expresses itself. It can be used to welcome and initiate communication between people and communities, but it can also be used as a means to erase, as with the Cahokia. Composition and composing are epistemological, and their use by different communities can give voice and impose silence. These practices were less obvious, as they weren’t explicitly explored, in my other two artifacts. However, the SpaceX webcast has the issue of welcoming people in, they needed to have the technological access and knowledge about the launch to find and engage with the community. The webcast itself is set up with multiple voices, angles, illustrations, and perspectives to serve as both a learning and advertising tool. Lastly, the homebrewing community uses composition to experiment and communicate. It can be interesting, as I’m doing right now, to play around with the constituent ingredients for a beer recipe to see what happens. This sense of play with the constituent piece of a composition appeared to be an important aspect of the community. Using other compositions, like community forums and websites, allows for a means of entry for interested people, though they can also be exclusionary in the expertise, vocabulary, and knowledge needed to approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, that composition is a process, with many voices and influences behind a composer, that may or may not be visible or expressed. All three of the artifacts and situations that I examined were explicitly communal, multi-authored, and multi-voiced. While not something that I particularly sought out, I was surprised at how overtly communal composition and composing can be. Malea Powell demonstrated this in her talk by assembling and negotiating between multiple voices and perspectives. It was also visually clear within the SpaceX webcast that there were multiple people, events, and compositions assembled together, with a variety of purposes, in the one webcast screen. And the homebrewing community is one that seems to show their collective interest in most things that they do. Recipes and experiments are composed collectively, with people drawing clearly on prior knowledge and precedent. There is also the critique and evaluation within the community of beer that has been brewed, with discussions on how best to adapt or develop new approaches within the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifth, that composition is rhetorical. This was an assumption of mine coming into the project, but I think it is worth exploring. Each of these artifacts had a clear rhetorical nature. All of the communities and compositions responded to some exigence, had an audience in mind, appealed to that audience, and hoped to influence them in some way. Malea Powell was very clearly addressing the audience at CCCCs and within the field. She wanted to bring attention to invisible issues of colonialism and to offer a space for different epistemologies. For SpaceX, there was the occasion of a rocket launch, but it was also their first flight back after an accident in September. This webcast was also composed for multiple audience that may or may not have similar reasons for watching, and they did their best to address those. The homebrewing community responds to and composes within the rhetorical situation of the hobby, with a variety of responses by and for different audiences based on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, composition is ecological in that it responds to, circulates, and evolves based on highly situated and interwoven processes, audiences, materials, and composers. Composing and composition exist within a variety of forces and situations, and it operates within those bounds. Compositions also evolve as they respond to and adapt for different situations. There also appears to be an intersection between organic responses and directed responses in how the ecology shapes composition and how compositions in turn shape future responses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, I found that this project extended or illuminated different aspects of composition and composition theory for me. However, as I was working through it, and the reflection especially, I kept feeling like I was playing Whack-A-Mole. I would have an idea, or a connection, and I would run towards it only to have another one pop up that I wanted to respond to. It was frustrating at times because I didn’t feel that I was able to dwell in one place or in one thought very long, and that I would shuffle off to the next. There are two things that this project primarily helped to illustrate to me, first, that composition and composing practices are socially situated and that they operate in rhetorical ecologies. These were both connections that I feel I have worked with before, but seeing them play out in a variety of contexts and practices here was really interesting. The process of examining composition and composing through these lenses offered a new, combined perspective that highlighted connections and centered social ecologies within composing for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusions</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 06:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an idea that is relatively new, but I think there is great promise in it. Working through the process of performing the revision narrative has been an interesting one. Its one that I knew wouldn&amp;#8217;t be easy, but has also proven to be more difficult than I had at first imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0415-e1462474741733.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0415-e1462474741733.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Process&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;40%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing has been purely logistical. In performing this on my WordPress site, I have had flexibility to move and connect things as I would like, to relate posts together through smart linking and decision trees.But I have found that the accounting requirements to keep track of the links and related elements difficult. I will need to develop a workflow to troubleshoot for students. There will need to be a certain amount of teaching the technology necessary in implementation. I think that it could be done in a similar hypertext, especially with the digital and multimodal affordances of WordPress as a platform, but there will need to be necessary development work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/memory.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/memory.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Memory&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;40%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the work with memory really surprising. I was fully expecting to find some interesting tidbits in my process. I&amp;#8217;ve always found that reflective and process texts very useful and enlightening. I wasn&amp;#8217;t expecting the level of play with my process to give me as much as it would, especially in considering what else I did while writing. There are other things that I could have accounted for in the text, from placement, to music, to equipment, to the choices that I make at different points related to my writing. When I work on paper, when I turn to a computer, the back-and-forth through research and writing and back again. I have always found my process iterative, going back through data and writing again and again, but I wasn&amp;#8217;t expecting the interplay with my process and memory in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Revision&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;33%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&#34;ui-id-2&#34;&gt;
  I did find that I was doing a fair amount of revision in the production of this text, especially in terms of how I was utilizing memory. In explicitly invoking and playing with memory, I found that I was often moving between paper notes, Evernote, word documents, and my WordPress site here. This interplay of memories and materials was important. This is really indicative of how memory is a generative force, and revision is a generative force, and how revision is a fully embodied process.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0261.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0261.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Play&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;33%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id=&#34;ui-id-3&#34;&gt;
  I found the ideas of play and gaming central to this work. This type of interactive process narrative asks for students to try, fail, revise, learn, and generate knowledge about themselves and how they think and write. The idea that play is important, though not always fun, and the permission to fail productively, was key to this idea and exploration of process and revision. The gamification, the idea of choices, and making evident the various choices was really important. In revisions of this idea, being able to better account for various choices, and having more time to think about and work through them, will be useful.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an approach that will continue to need to be revised and worked with. I think that&amp;#8217;s what is so exciting about this, is that it wants to continue to be played with. I don&amp;#8217;t know how students will react to this, but I think that it could be a really productive, different, and generative way for them to engage with writing. I think this is especially true in the ways that they are asked to utilize memory as a generative force.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 06:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You open up healy.gwp.draft2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    [aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;#8221; name=&amp;#8221;Revision&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;center&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;100%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s time to get serious with this article! There are a number of reasons for your wanting to do this. First, you really like this idea, think it has great potential, works with your interests, and you&amp;#8217;ve had some luck using it in your own classrooms. In fact, this semester the workshop quest seemed to work really well for a number of your students, with them starting to better see the connections between peer-review and their work, both as readers and as writers. But this stuff is hard, and you&amp;#8217;re struggling with entering into this new discourse. Some of it is time and timing, you&amp;#8217;ve not been at this very long, there is also the part that it is just plain difficult, and you don&amp;#8217;t always get it quite yet. But you&amp;#8217;re trying to make a rhetorically effective document, one that appeals to your audience of other writing teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You work on bringing together your research, your position, your findings, and your ideas. You type away, bring parts in from your literature review document, integrating them, seeing how the ideas mesh. You continue to work on the article until there is not much left to do, at least not at this point in time, at least not until you can give your process and memory more time to work it over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things go well with the article. You revise and integrate until you turn it in to *hopefully* complete your independent study. You are proud of what you put together, but also realize that there is a lot of work left to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been really interesting going back through your process in creating this narrative. There are some places where you see potentials for improvement, for re-seeing your process. There are some shortcomings, but you like where its gotten you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/conclusions/&#34;&gt;Click to continue on to the conclusion&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serious Revisions</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-serious-revisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 06:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-serious-revisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You stare at the open document. You&amp;#8217;ve pulled together quotes and research notes. The weight of doing the revisions in situ seem overwhelming. You open a new document, title it Literature Review, and start typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start with the major moves that you&amp;#8217;ve seen in connecting to your own work. You create a set of bullet points that lay out your thoughts and the themes you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process and Revision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peer-Review and Troubles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshop as a collaborative and process space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multimodality/Literacy/Connections between Peer-Review, Workshop, Gaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gamification as a Method of Connecting Process, Peer-Review, and Collaboration in the Workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve laid it out and see the major moves, you start typing away. You integrate quotes, paraphrase, summarize, cut, paste, expand, and bridge. You feel like you&amp;#8217;ve started to create and carve out your own space. It doesn&amp;#8217;t feel quite right yet though. You keep working on it, pushing and pulling. Revising and seeing where it goes. You work on it until it spans almost 5 pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now its time to integrate it back into the rest of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/integration/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Work on integrating the Literature Review into your main body?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/run/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Go for run?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gamed Process Narrative</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-the-gamed-process-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 05:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-the-gamed-process-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within this particular pedagogy students are asked to go back through their writing process and to create an interactive revision text. This is set up as a way for students to think about and play with memory. It is a way for them to engage with their writing in their memory as they account for how it came into being. There are a few pieces of this assignment that seem important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first is to address the audience as a player, as someone actively working through the revision process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should account for a number of the major steps and choices that students made in writing and revision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should account for alternatives, or paths not taken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should allow for interaction by and from the audience and they play with and through the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, I would like to attempt an interactive revision text of my own. I am accounting for the process of writing and revision an article length piece that deals with gamification and the workshop (notice a theme).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this I have gone through my memory to work through and account for my own revision process. This has also been necessarily informed by this project and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/more-revision-narrative/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Time to start the narrative.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 05:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-09-run/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You lace up your shoes, your new shoes, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.altrarunning.com/men/torin-20&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Altra Torin 2.0s&lt;/a&gt;. The ones you just got last week. The ones that feel good in the way that only new shoes can. You head out into the neighborhood, your work on the tip of your mind. You click your watch to record the miles and head out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You return home after about a 30-45 minutes, somewhere between 3 and 5 miles done. It felt good, you need a shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/more-revision-narrative/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Its time to return to work.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revise Literature Review</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-revise-literature-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-revise-literature-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You stare at the literature review section of your article. This is one section that you really need to revise. It is unclear what work you&amp;#8217;ve done, what the gap is, and how you fit in. Come on Michael, you can do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You open Evernote and locate your research notes. First you create a list with the movements of the research. You have questions like &amp;#8220;Why do peer review?&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Why is it difficult?&amp;#8221; In a list under these you&amp;#8217;ve put names like Barron, Bishop, Bruffee, Trimbur, Mayers, Jung, Yancey, Hesse, and Alexander. You start to see how they relate to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some are grouped around literacy, others the workshop, other gamification, and others still on collaboration. You start to maybe see how they interact, and where you fit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/reading-and-research/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Do more research?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/serious-revisions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Start some serious revisions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading and Research</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-reading-and-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-reading-and-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of doing any writing you choose to go back and do more research. You&amp;#8217;ve already read three books in relationship to this article by now. What else do you need? Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours later, and no further writing on your draft, you have a new stack of articles that seem related. You&amp;#8217;ve also thought about other potentials for revision, peer-review, creative writing, and multimodality that need researching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You decide that you could research forever if you wanted to. You open healy.gwp.draft1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/more-revision-narrative/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Return to writing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Revision Narrative</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-more-revision-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-more-revision-narrative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whoa, that was a lot of work. I hope that you haven&amp;#8217;t been lost. I&amp;#8217;ve often felt lost as I&amp;#8217;ve explored these areas, memories, and my own process. Now that that&amp;#8217;s out of the way, lets continue back on to adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You rename the document &amp;#8220;healy.gwp.draft1&amp;#8221; and read through your work. There are some decent ideas here. You like what you&amp;#8217;ve done. However, given the reading, there is a big gap in the theory section. In fact, the literature review seems rather thin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do next?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/reading-and-research/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Proceed with more reading and research?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/revise-literature-review/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Revise the literature review section?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/run/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Close the document and go for a run?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cast of Characters</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-cast-of-characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-cast-of-characters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Revision&amp;#8221; caption=&amp;#8221;Mardi, the mascot of revision. It is also fun to post pictures of the pup.&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;50%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/memory.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/memory.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Memory&amp;#8221; caption=&amp;#8221;The operator.&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;50%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0415-e1462474741733.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0415-e1462474741733.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Process&amp;#8221; caption=&amp;#8221;It&amp;#8217;s work, it takes time.&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;left&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;50%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0261.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0261.jpg&amp;amp;#8221&lt;/a&gt;; name=&amp;#8221;Gaming&amp;#8221; caption=&amp;#8221;The idea of gaming and play is important for the connections between memory and revision.&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;50%&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]&lt;div&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/questions-and-background/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Follow on for key questions and background information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrance</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-entrance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-entrance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You find yourself sitting in a room. There is a computer in front of you playing music. There is a cup of coffee on the desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You take a drink and start to type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve been working on a piece that you&amp;#8217;ve titled: &amp;#8220;It’s Dangerous to Go Alone! Take This&amp;#8221;: Co-op Play and the Gamified Workshop.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s a piece that you&amp;#8217;ve been working on since taking &lt;em&gt;Creative Writing Pedagogy&lt;/em&gt; last fall. This article discusses a gamified workshop pedagogy. You&amp;#8217;ve revised, and rethought it, and revised again. You used it as your writing sample for applying to PhD programs. You&amp;#8217;re trying to get it ready for publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just recently you&amp;#8217;ve completely overhauled the lit review section, hopefully crafting a theoretical space from which to operate. It seems to have worked, even though it was difficult to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You stand here now, thinking about the process and how it started. Trying to dive into memory to account for the work that you&amp;#8217;ve done to date. A simple accounting: at least 10 named drafts as its moved from the germ of an idea to where it stands now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with you for this adventure are a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/cast-of-characters/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cast of Characters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Works Cited</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-works-cited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 20:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-works-cited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aguilar, Stephen J., Caitlin Holman, and Barry J. Fishman. “Game-Inspired Design: Empirical Evidence in Support of Gameful Learning Environments.” &lt;em&gt;Games and Culture&lt;/em&gt; (2015): 1-27. Web. &lt;em&gt;Sage Journals&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alexander, Jonathan. “Gaming, Student Literacies, and the Composition Classroom: Some Possibilities for Transformation.” &lt;em&gt;College Composition and Communication&lt;/em&gt; 61.1 (2009): 35-63. Web. &lt;em&gt;JSTOR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Augustine. “The Confessions of Saint Augustine: Book X.” Web. &lt;em&gt;Blackboard&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Word&lt;/em&gt; File.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bailey, Wm. Ruffin. “Hacks, Mods, Easter Eggs, and Fossils: Intentionality and Digitalism in the Video Game.” &lt;em&gt;Playing the Past: History and Nostalgia in Video Games&lt;/em&gt;. Eds. Whalen, Zach, and Laurie N. Taylor. Nashville: Vanderbilt UP, 2008. 69-90. Ebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barry, Lynda. &lt;em&gt;What it Is&lt;/em&gt;. Quebec: Drawn &amp;amp; Quarterly, 2008. Print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campbell, James. “Just Less than Total War: Simulating World War II as Ludic Nostalgia.” &lt;em&gt;Playing the Past: History and Nostalgia in Video Games&lt;/em&gt;. Eds. Whalen, Zach, and Laurie N. Taylor. Nashville: Vanderbilt UP, 2008. 183-200. Ebook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gee, James Paul. &lt;em&gt;What Video Games Have to Teach Us About Learning and Literacy&lt;/em&gt;. Revised and Updated ed. New York: Palgrave Macmillan, 2007. Print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hampl, Patricia. “Memory and Imagination.” &lt;em&gt;I Could Tell You Stories: Sojourns in the Land of Memory&lt;/em&gt;. New York: W.W. Norton. 1999. Print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jung, Julie. “Writing that Listens.” &lt;em&gt;Revisionary Rhetoric, Feminist Pedagogy, and Multigenre Texts.&lt;/em&gt; 2005: 1-28. PDF File. &lt;em&gt;Blackboard&lt;/em&gt;. Web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kuhn, Annette. “A Journey through Memory.” &lt;em&gt;Memory and Methodology&lt;/em&gt;. New York. 2000: 179-196. PDF File. Web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lehrer, Jonah. “Marcel Proust: The Method of Memory.” &lt;em&gt;Proust was a Neuroscientist&lt;/em&gt;. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 2007. 75-95. PDF File. &lt;em&gt;Blackboard&lt;/em&gt;. Web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rider, Janine. &lt;em&gt;The Writer’s Book of Memory: An Interdisciplinary Study for Writing Teachers&lt;/em&gt;. Mahwah: Lawernce Erlbaum, 1995. Print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shipka, Jody. &amp;#8220;Negotiating Rhetorical, Material, Methodological, and Technological Difference: Evaluating Multimodal Designs.&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;College Composition and Communication&lt;/em&gt; 61.1 (2009): 343-366. Web. &lt;em&gt;JSTOR&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sloan, Robin J. S. “Videogames as Remediated Memories: Commodified Nostalgia and Hyperreality in Far Cry 3: Blood Dragon and Gone Home.” &lt;em&gt;Games and Culture&lt;/em&gt; 10.6 (2015): 525-550. Web. &lt;em&gt;Sage Journals&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell, Dave. “Beyond Mnemotechnics: Confession and Memory in Augustine.” &lt;em&gt;Philosophy and Rhetoric&lt;/em&gt; 39.3 (2006): 233-253. Web. &lt;em&gt;Blackboard&lt;/em&gt;. PDF File.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobin, Lad. “Process Pedagogy.” &lt;em&gt;A Guide to Composition Pedagogies&lt;/em&gt; 2001: 1-18. PDF File &lt;em&gt;Blackboard&lt;/em&gt;. Web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yancey, Kathleen Blake. “Made not Only in Words: Composition in a New Key.” &lt;em&gt;College Composition and Communication&lt;/em&gt; 56.2 (2004): 297-325. Web. &lt;em&gt;JSTOR&lt;/em&gt;. 13 Apr. 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211;. &amp;#8220;Postmodernism, Palimpsest, and Portfolios: Theoretical Issues in the Representation of Student Work.&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;ePortfolio Performance Support Systems: Constructing, Presenting, and Assessing Portfolios&lt;/em&gt;. Eds. Katherine V. Wills and Rich Rice. Fort Collins: The WAC Clearinghouse and Parlor Press, 2013: 19-39. PDF File. Web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
<<<<<<< HEAD
    <item>
      <title>Literature Review</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-literature-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 19:33:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/gamed_peer_review/2016-05-05-literature-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-has-been-said-already&#34;&gt;What has been said already?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Memory:
  &lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    [aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/memory.jpg&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;400px&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    I would like to start with a number of ideas with memory. The first is to go way back to Augustine and to the idea that memory is a generative force, that “when I speak, the images of all I speak of are present, out of the same treasury of memory; nor would I speak of any thereof, were the images wanting” (Augustine 5). That, as Augustine says &amp;#8220;the art of memory and the art of rhetoric are deeply interdependent&amp;#8221; (Tell 236). That working with memory means creating and playing with stuff. Or, as Lynda Barry asks, &amp;#8220;What is the past made (from) of?&amp;#8221; (19). An as she continues, in order think and create we need to play, and that play isn&amp;#8217;t always fun, but it&amp;#8217;s always generative (51-52).
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Play with memory is especially generative, because as &amp;#8221; Proust knew: the past is never past. As long as we are alive, our memories remain wonderfully volatile. In their mercurial mirror we see ourselves” (Lehrer 95). The key with play as a generative force is that “memory’s not a stable repository of the past; instead it is reconstructive and creative, dependent on past, present, and future” (Rider 82). And most importantly, memory is not a static thing, it
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      in any case, is always already secondary revision: even the memories we run and rerun inside our heads are residues of physical process, often unconscious ones; and their (re)telling—putting subjective memory-images into some communicable form—always involves ordering and organizing them in one way or another (Kuhn 184).
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Memory work, as Annette Kuhn discusses, is “an active practice of remembering which takes an inquiring attitude towards the past and the activity of its (re)construction through memory” (Kuhn 186). And with this framing of memory work, it is important to see that to live and write and play with the past is to relive and inhabit it, to live it twice (Hampl 36-7). Using memory in composition and revision is especially important as it asks our students to engage with themselves now and in the past to best communicate.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    This is especially vital for the work of students, to see how their memories are generative and lived experiences. That when they are in the classroom or the world and engaging rhetorically, that they are playing with memory, they are recognizing genres and conventions, they are being asked to play with their memories. And its not always fun, but its important. That when “we teach our students to search, use, and value their own memories when they write, we foster rhetoric that breaks out of the chains of standardized thinking and writing” (Rider 108). Memory becomes an operative and playful force, it lets the generation of thought and interaction function. Memory is vital for the functioning of language and its tempering through revision. Memory studies helps us better understand revision by helping us better understand how we connect to others through memory.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Process:
  &lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    [aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0415-e1462474741733.jpg&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;400px&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Process is hard work. It requires us to engage with ourselves, our writing, and each other repeatably. It takes time and effort. As Donald Murray says, its “the process of using language to learn about our world, to evaluate what we learn about our world, to communicate what we learn about our world” (Murray 4). In composition, the writing process underlies much of what we do, how we teach, and how we see the world. To use language is to act rhetorically, which is to engage with process with the world. In assessing process, we have devised a number of ways to think about and have students think about it. We&amp;#8217;ve thought up methods of assessment and assignment that ask students to engage, again and again, with the writing process, and to “help students see how text and writers and readers are always and inevitably embedded in multiple contexts and cultures” (Tobin 16). We&amp;#8217;ve turned towards reflection, process narratives, and portfolios as ways to help students see and account for the process work that they have done so that “students are provided with an incentive to consider how, why, when, and for whom texts, their own as well as those composed by others, make any kind of meaning at all” (Shipka W355). We&amp;#8217;ve looked at a variety of ways and methods for them to see process and to experience the generative play of memory and revision.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    What seems most vital in the teaching and assessing of process is for students to “speak to the shifting relationships between context and text” (Yancey 22 “Postmodern”) as they are “all oriented to the circulation of texts, to genre, to media, and to the ways that writing gets made, both individually and culturally” (Yancey “Made not only in Words” 315). Using process, portfolios, and careful assessment we can see to “the inclusion of these contexts in our teaching and learning as a kind of palimpsest makes meaning more complex, more sophisticated (if not always more immediately coherent) as it makes it more specific, less anonymous” (Yancey 23 “Postmodern”). Process is a way to help students see the layers and they are put down, iterated on, changed, and adapted. These process practices make sure that “students must attend to the impact of their writerly choices as well as to the visual, material, and technological aspects of their texts and practices” (Shipka W355). If the goal is for students to evolve in their awareness of process and rhetoric, then an inclusion of memory and play at the center of pedagogy appears necessary. Memory offers a way to peal back, account for, assess, and see the layers the process has built up.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Revision:
  &lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    [aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0406.jpg&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;400px&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    The most visible piece of process for many students is revision, it is also one of the most difficult for students to engage meaningfully with. This, in many ways, is due to how “we have failed to theorize how readers and writers contend with the inevitable disconnections that permeate their experiences with texts” (Jung 11) as they move through process from writers to readers and back again. For growth in writing, student “writers need to see that logic, imagination, and reason, not obscure rules, motivate everything writers do, every comment teacher and editors make” (Deither 7). They need to make the connections between what they are doing as the author and the feedback of their audience. By having students &amp;#8220;engag[e] in rigorous self-reflection while reading and writing, thinkers become revisers connecting with other revisers and themselves” (Jung 28). If we can make the connections for students between process, revision, and intent, they can start to see how memory can functions and a generative force.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    An important aspect of revision is allowing students to try and fail, and having that be a part of the learning process. They have to be allowed to see how, as Lynda Barry puts it, their thoughts have mass and weight. They need to space to play in order to see how they operate together. To see, &amp;#8220;to admit that memory is not a warehouse of finished stories, not a gallery of framed pictures” (Hampl 26). That memory is a thing to be worked through, like writing, like language, like living. That play and memory have vital functions in revision and process, and that its not always fun, but it is necessary.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Gaming:
  &lt;/h2&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    [aesop_character img=&amp;#8221;http://www.michaelhealy.info/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/img_0261.jpg&amp;#8221; align=&amp;#8221;right&amp;#8221; width=&amp;#8221;400px&amp;#8221; force_circle=&amp;#8221;off&amp;#8221;]
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Here is where I see gaming and gamification having immense potential in the teaching of rhetoric and composition. As James Paul Gee discusses, good games have learning principle built in, and they let players explore them as they are challenged, fail, learn, and ultimately enjoy the game. Games are a “always actively assembled (or changed) by the player, on the spot, in terms of images, materials, dialogue, and embodied actions in the virtual world being mutually created by the game and the player” (Gee 82). Games exist at an interactive intersection between author and audience, where both have agency in the playing and experience of the game. Games offer a place to think and have students:
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      consider connections &lt;em&gt;across modes of writing and writing environments&lt;/em&gt; cuts to the heart of what we as compositionist &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be doing: offering students a diversity of writing experiences &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; encouraging them to become more &lt;em&gt;conscious&lt;/em&gt; writers—that is, writers rhetorically aware of how audience, genre, and tone work in a variety of writing environments (Alexander 59)
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Games offer a rich and revisionary memory space. The popularity of nostalgic and history video games shows that “it is this memory of the real that is most valuable to the consumer seeking catharsis through participation in a richly nostalgic simulation” (Sloan 547). Video games offer a way to engage the past, play with it, play in it, and play from it. They offer a rich space from which to have students engage and play with their texts, even if they don&amp;#8217;t realize the are engaged in a gamified pedagogy. The strength of gaming is in its ability to &amp;#8220;demand critical attention in order to understand better how the history of past media bears upon the present&amp;#8221; (Taylor and Whalen 13). Combining memory with gaming the ability to frame and give a broader context that accounts for individuals and their experiences.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Gaming also gives students the time and space to ask, and see, how the world and the greater context is interacting with themselves. They can produce and examine games to see “the opportunity to engage with their courses in a deep way that encourages mastery over performance” (Aguilar et al 23) and to experience how “even in the most complicated piece of branching logic, entry into each potential branch is, at its core, mediated by a simple test of true/false (that is, Boolean) logic” (Bailey 72). Gaming combine with memory, and the choices evoked, is a rich rhetorical space. Gaming, and gamed environments, allow for students to see and play with memory in a way that other mediums don&amp;#8217;t always allow.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/the-gamed-process-narrative/&#34;&gt;With that necessary background explored, shall we return to the narrative?&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.michaelhealy.info/2016/05/works-cited/&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
=======
>>>>>>> working
  </channel>
</rss>
