<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Michael Healy</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Michael Healy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Your Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/academic/talk/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>At Play with Composition: Explorations of Voice</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/samla2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/samla2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am studying the efficacy of play as an organizational and pedagogical theory in ENC 2135. I am interested in students’ perceptions on play within the composition classroom, especially in the development of voice and agency in their writing. I have anecdotally seen it as a positive influence through my teaching, but I want something more empirical that I can build from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do the study I have prepared a material’s release form and a short survey to distribute to students. I have arranged for the distribution and collection of these materials. I will use these responses, student reflections, and student evaluations to read and code for play, voice, and agency. I will be focusing on a peer review exercise that has students speed date a draft, a collaborative activity that asks students to inhabit inquiry, and the semester reflection letter for their ePortfolios. I will develop a coding scheme (at this point I’m unsure if it will be deductive or inductive) to examine the written materials. I will use the coding, surveys, and my own observations to help triangulate the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to see first, what students think about a play infused classroom through these activities, and second, to see if there is evidence of efficacy within their reflective writings, evaluations, and surveys. I will be analyzing data over the summer. My intentions with the data analysis and presentation is to offer a way of developing voice in the composition classroom as a strategy that students can utilize.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circulation, Narrative, and Human Rights: New Materialism meets Spectacular Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/femrhet2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/femrhet2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ludic Revision</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/cccc2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 21:47:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/cccc2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Grandma: (Re)Making (or Appropriating?) Agency in the Archive</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/femrhet2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/academic/talk/femrhet2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;lO3rp1%J7IPa&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
