<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eportfolio on Michael Healy</title>
    <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/tags/eportfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eportfolio on Michael Healy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Your Name</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/academic/tags/eportfolio/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Theories of Composition ePortfolio</title>
      <link>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelhealy.space/academic/project/eportfolios/comptheory/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This is my Spring 2017 Composition Theory ePortfolio. The links go to the individual components that have been selected for inclusion. The selections here represent some of the work of this semester though is not inclusive. I also intend for these selections and reflections to look back to what I brought into the class, what I learned here, and forward to new contexts. At the bottom of this page are links to and brief descriptions of each artifact collected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall reflection for the ePortfolio will guide you through the reading and connections. As you read through the reflection, the artifacts that I mention will be linked and open in new tabs, so that specifics of what I mention will be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-reflection-reflection&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reflection&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Final Reflection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This serves as a synthesis of the artifacts collected within this ePortfolio. This reflection works with the themes and readings of the class to illustrate the selections, while also looking beyond the classroom context to how the learning and artifacts function more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;triptych-plus-project-triptych&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;triptych&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Triptych Plus Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project examines three different perspectives on composition: Homebrewing Community, a SpaceX hosted webcast for a rocket launch, and Malea Powell&amp;rsquo;s 2012 CCCCs chairs address. The above link will take you directly to the reflective overlay, which then links to the individual panels of the triptych. This organization mirrors the theological art use of a triptych, with the overall theme opening up to reveal the interior workings, which is present in the &lt;a href=&#34;triptychreflection&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Triptych Plus Reflective Overlay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;perspective-project-perspectives&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;perspectives&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Perspective Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This link connects to my video interview with Ned Stuckey-French on composition and his composition process. The video essay, based around the recorded interview is featured, along with an additional reflection and provided links on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;below-are-three-selections-with-reflections-from-the-class-this-semester&#34;&gt;Below are three selections, with reflections, from the class this semester.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-one-and-reflection-situating-composition-studies-selection1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection One and Reflection: Situating Composition Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This selection is an SRR that examines the history and evolution of composition in universities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-two-and-reflection-processing-assumptions-selection2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection Two and Reflection: Processing Assumptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post that takes a different perspective on the development of composition as a discipline based on the research being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;selection-three-and-reflection-writing-program-acronyms-considering-contexts-systems-and-locales-selection3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;selection3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Selection Three and Reflection: Writing Program Acronyms: Considering Contexts, Systems, and Locales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SRR examines the history and taxonomies of different WAC/WID programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-outside-artifact-selections&#34;&gt;Two Outside Artifact Selections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry-https-atplaywithcomposition-wordpress-com-exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://atplaywithcomposition.wordpress.com/exploratory-2-interest-and-inquiry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Exploratory 2: Interest and Inquiry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an assignment prompt from my 2135 class that I&amp;rsquo;m teaching this semester. I chose this because of the pedagogical connections between composition theory and what I am teaching. I also chose it because the prompt and activity was influenced by work in collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities-https-digitalscholars-wordpress-com-2017-02-12-look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalscholars.wordpress.com/2017/02/12/look-at-all-this-stuff-on-playing-printing-and-virtual-reality-in-the-digital-humanities/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Look at all this Stuff! On Playing, Printing, and Virtual Reality in the Digital Humanities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a blog post that I composed as an introduction to a digital scholars meeting. This was a synthesis of the readings and materials for the week, and was situated within a very specific rhetorical ecology and responded to a set of exigencies. I also chose it due to the content of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-project-abstract-abstract&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Final Project Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This connects to my final project abstract, which involves a short study from my teaching this semester that looks at play, voice, and pedagogy, and seeks to study the efficacy of play in students use of voice in 2135. I am targeting SAMLA for the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icons made by Freepik from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flaticon.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.flaticon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
